{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Information Management",
    "Term": "Prelims",
    "Title": "Database Models",
    "LastModified": "17 May 2024",
    "Authors": [
      ""
    ],
    "References": [
      "Any external links/handouts should be referenced here"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "Focuses on how the database structure will be used to store and manage end-user data.",
      "answer": "Database Design",
      "choices": [
        "Database Design",
        "Data Modeling",
        "Data Model",
        "Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This refers on the process of creating a specific data model for a determined problem domain.",
      "answer": "Data Modeling",
      "choices": [
        "Database Design",
        "Data Modeling",
        "Data Model",
        "Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This refers to the first step in designing a database.",
      "answer": "Data Modeling",
      "choices": [
        "Database Design",
        "Data Modeling",
        "Data Model",
        "Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This refers to a relatively simple representation that is usually graphical.",
      "answer": "Data Model",
      "choices": [
        "Database Design",
        "Data Modeling",
        "Data Model",
        "Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This refers to a representation of more complex real-world data structures.",
      "answer": "Data Model",
      "choices": [
        "Database Design",
        "Data Modeling",
        "Data Model",
        "Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This refers to an abstraction of a more complex real-world object or event.",
      "answer": "Model",
      "choices": [
        "Database Design",
        "Data Modeling",
        "Data Model",
        "Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Data models can facilitate interaction among the designer, the applications programmer, and the end user.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "A well-developed data model can even foster improved understanding of the organization for which the database design is developed.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The importance of data modeling cannot be understated.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ constitutes the most basic information used by a system.",
      "answer": "Data",
      "choices": [
        "Data",
        "Entity",
        "Attribute",
        "Applications"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ are created to manage data and to help transform data into information.",
      "answer": "Applications",
      "choices": [
        "Data",
        "Entity",
        "Attribute",
        "Applications"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Data is viewed the same ways by different people.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The following are the basic building blocks for data model EXCEPT ONE.",
      "answer": "Information",
      "choices": [
        "Entity",
        "Attribute",
        "Relationship",
        "Information"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model basic building block refers to a person, place, thing, or event about which data will be collected and stored.",
      "answer": "Entity",
      "choices": [
        "Entity",
        "Attribute",
        "Relationship",
        "Information"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model basic building block refers to a characteristic of an entity.",
      "answer": "Attribute",
      "choices": [
        "Entity",
        "Attribute",
        "Relationship",
        "Information"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model basic building block refers to an association among entitites.",
      "answer": "Relationship",
      "choices": [
        "Entity",
        "Attribute",
        "Relationship",
        "Information"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are the three types of relationships EXCEPT ONE.",
      "answer": "Many-to-one",
      "choices": [
        "One-to-one",
        "One-to-many",
        "Many-to-one",
        "Many-to-many"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model was developed in the 1960s to manage large amounts of data for complex manufacturing projects.",
      "answer": "Hierarchical Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model was created to represent complex data relationships more effectively than the hierarchical model in order to improve database performance, and to impose a database standard.",
      "answer": "Network Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model was introduced in 1970 by E.F. Codd of IBM.",
      "answer": "Relational Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model was introduced in 1976 by Peter Chen.",
      "answer": "Entity Relationship Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model's basic logical structure is represented by an upside-down tree that contains levels, or segments.",
      "answer": "Hierarchical Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model's segment is the equivalent of a file system's record type.",
      "answer": "Hierarchical Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model is generally used today.",
      "answer": "Network Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model represented a major breakthrough for both users and designers.",
      "answer": "Relational Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model uses a foundatinal mathematical concept known as a relation.",
      "answer": "Relational Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This data model's graphical representation of entitites and their relationships in a database structure complemented the relational data model concepts.",
      "answer": "Entity Relationship Model",
      "choices": [
        "Hierarchical Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This standard database concept of a network model refer to the conceptual organization of the entire database as viewed by the database administrator.",
      "answer": "Schema",
      "choices": [
        "Schema",
        "Subscema",
        "Data Manipulation Language",
        "Data Definition Language"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This standard database concept of a network model defines the portion of the database by the application programs that actually produce the desired information from the data in the database.",
      "answer": "Subschema",
      "choices": [
        "Schema",
        "Subscema",
        "Data Manipulation Language",
        "Data Definition Language"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This standard database concept of a network model defines the environment in which data can be managed.",
      "answer": "Data Manipulation Language",
      "choices": [
        "Schema",
        "Subscema",
        "Data Manipulation Language",
        "Data Definition Language"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This standard database concept of a network model allows the database administrator to define the schema components.",
      "answer": "Data Definition Language",
      "choices": [
        "Schema",
        "Subscema",
        "Data Manipulation Language",
        "Data Definition Language"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Increasingly complex real-world problems demonstrated a need for a data model that more closely represented the real world.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this data model, both data and its relationships are contained in a single structure known as an object.",
      "answer": "Object-Oriented Data Model",
      "choices": [
        "Object-Oriented Data Model",
        "Network Model",
        "Relational Model",
        "Entity Relationship Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does OODBMS mean? It is which the Object-Oriented Data Model is the basis of.",
      "answer": "Object-Oriented Database Management System",
      "choices": [
        "Object-Oriented Database Management System",
        "Object-Oriented Data Management System",
        "Object-Oriented Data Manager System",
        "Object-Oriented Database Manager System"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that an object is an abstraction of a real-world entity.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that an attribute is the properties of a class.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that objects share similar characteristics are grouped in classes.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that a class is a collection of similar objects with shared structure and behavior.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that class are organized in an object hierarchy.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that a class hierarchy resembles a downright up tree in which each class has only one parent.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that inheritance is the ability of an object within the class hierarchy to inherit attribute.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This component of OODBM says that Object-Oriented Data Models are typically depicted using Unified Modeling Language (UML) class diagrams.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is a metalanguage used to represent and manipulate data elements and permits the manipulation of a document's data elements.",
      "answer": "Extensible Markup Language",
      "choices": [
        "Extensible Markup Language",
        "Hypertext Markup Language",
        "Object-Oriented Language",
        "Filipino Language"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Unlike other markup languages, XML permits the manipulation of a document's data elements.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "It refers to a movement to find new and better ways to manage large amounts of web and sensor-generated data.",
      "answer": "Big Data",
      "choices": [
        "Big Data",
        "Training Data",
        "Mobile Data",
        "Sensor Data"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The term 'Big Data' have been first used in a computing framework by ____________ who is a Silicon Graphics scientist in the 1990s.",
      "answer": "John Mashley",
      "choices": [
        "John Mashley",
        "Mash Burnedead",
        "John Coronel",
        "Douglas Laney"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "____________ first described the basic characteristics of Big Data databases.",
      "answer": "Douglas Laney",
      "choices": [
        "John Mashley",
        "Mash Burnedead",
        "John Coronel",
        "Douglas Laney"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The following are the characteristics of Big Data databases EXCEPT ONE.",
      "answer": "Agility",
      "choices": [
        "Volume",
        "Velocity",
        "Variety",
        "Agility"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a Big Data Database refers to the amount of data being stored.",
      "answer": "Volume",
      "choices": [
        "Volume",
        "Velocity",
        "Variety",
        "Agility"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a Big Data Database refers to the speed with which data grows and the need to process this data quickly in order to generate information and insight.",
      "answer": "Velocity",
      "choices": [
        "Volume",
        "Velocity",
        "Variety",
        "Agility"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic refers to the fact that the data being collected comes in multiple data formats.",
      "answer": "Variety",
      "choices": [
        "Volume",
        "Velocity",
        "Variety",
        "Agility"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is a large-scale distributed database system that stores structured and unstructured data in efficient ways.",
      "answer": "NoSQL",
      "choices": [
        "NoSQL",
        "Big Data Database",
        "Large Language Model Database",
        "SQL"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a NoSQL database entails that they are not based on the relational model and SQL, hence the name NoSQL.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a NoSQL database entails that it doesn't support distributed database architectures.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a NoSQL database entails that it provides high scalability, availability, and fault tolerance.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a NoSQL database entails that it doesn't support large amounts of sparse data.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This characteristic of a NoSQL database entails that it is geared toward performance rather than transaction consistency.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE .",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ."
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the big advantages of NoSQL databases is that they generally use a _____________ database node.",
      "answer": "Distributed",
      "choices": [
        "Distribute",
        "Relational",
        "Hierarchical",
        "Network"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "NoSQL databases can handle very high volumes of data and is suited for ___________ data.",
      "answer": "Sparse",
      "choices": [
        "Sparse",
        "Little",
        "Dry",
        "Large"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "NoSQL databases are designed to support ________ operations.",
      "answer": "Web",
      "choices": [
        "Web",
        "Desktop",
        "Offline",
        "Hard-coded"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the biggest problems of very large distributed databases are enforcing _______________.",
      "answer": "Data consistency",
      "choices": [
        "Data consistency",
        "Data redundancy",
        "Data safety",
        "Data security"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Distributed databases automatically make copies of data elements at ____________________ to ensure high availability and fault tolerance.",
      "answer": "Multiple nodes",
      "choices": [
        "Multiple nodes",
        "Multiple files",
        "Multiple save points",
        "Multiple check points"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This institute defined a framework for data modeling based on degrees of data abstraction in the early 1970s.",
      "answer": "American National Standards Institute Standards Planning and Requirements Committee",
      "choices": [
        "American National Standards Institute Standards Planning and Requirements Committee",
        "American Institute for Standards Planning and Requirements Committee",
        "American National Institute for Standards Planning and Committee of Requirements",
        "American Committee for National Standards and Planning Institute"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are the three levels of data abstraction as defined by the resulting ANSI/SPARC architecture EXCEPT ONE.",
      "answer": "Distributed Model",
      "choices": [
        "Distributed Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction is the end user's view of the data environment.",
      "answer": "External Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction refers to people who use the application programs to manipulate the data and generate information.",
      "answer": "External Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This schema of a level of data abstraction is a specific representation of its external model, using the database constructs supported by the chosen database.",
      "answer": "External Schema",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Schema",
        "External Schema",
        "Conceptual Schema",
        "Internal Schema"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction represents a global view of the entire database by the entire organization.",
      "answer": "Conceptual Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This schema of level of data abstraction is the basis for the identification and high-level description of the main data objects.",
      "answer": "Conceptual Schema",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Schema",
        "External Schema",
        "Conceptual Schema",
        "Internal Schema"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction is the representation of the database a seen by the DBMS.",
      "answer": "Internal Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction requires the designer to match the conceptual model's characteristics and constraints to those of the selected implementation model.",
      "answer": "Internal Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This schema of a level of data abstraction is a specific representation of its model, using the database constructs supported by the chosen database.",
      "answer": "Internal Schema",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Schema",
        "External Schema",
        "Conceptual Schema",
        "Internal Schema"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction operates at the lowest level, describing the way data is saved on storage media such as magnetic, solid state, or optical media.",
      "answer": "Physical Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This level of data abstraction requires the definition of both real-world storage devices and access ethods required to reach the data within those storage devices, making it both software and hardware dependent.",
      "answer": "Physical Model",
      "choices": [
        "Physical Model",
        "External Model",
        "Conceptual Model",
        "Internal Model"
      ],
      "reference": "02_Handout_1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    }
  ]
}
